<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowledge_base>
<entity wiki_title="Hoodoo_Man_Blues" type="UKN" id="E0584544" name="Hoodoo Man Blues">
<facts class="Infobox Album">
<fact name="Name">Hoodoo Man Blues</fact>
<fact name="Type">studio</fact>
<fact name="Artist"><link entity_id="E0187433">Junior Wells' Chicago Blues Band</link></fact>
<fact name="Released">1965</fact>
<fact name="Recorded">Sept. 22 – Sept. 23, 1965</fact>
<fact name="Genre"><link entity_id="E0124098">Blues</link></fact>
<fact name="Length">46:30</fact>
<fact name="Label"><link>Delmark</link></fact>
<fact name="Producer"><link>Bob Koester</link></fact>
<fact name="Reviews"><link entity_id="E0153126">Allmusic</link> link</fact>
<fact name="This album">Hoodoo Man Blues
(1965)</fact>
<fact name="Next album"><link>It's My Life, Baby!</link>
(1966)</fact>
</facts>
<wiki_text><![CDATA[Hoodoo Man Blues

Hoodoo Man Blues is the 1965 debut album of blues vocalist and harmonica player
Junior Wells, performing with the Junior Wells' Chicago Blues Band, an early
collaboration with Grammy Award-winning artist Buddy Guy. Released on LP by
Delmark Records, the album has been subsequently reissued on CD and LP by
Delmark and Analogue Productions.

The album of Chicago blues music was solicited by Bob Koester, the founder of
Delmark Records, who liked Wells' music enough to give the musician considerable
freedom on the album in spite of concerns of commercial response. The resultant
innovative album became Delmark's best seller, establishing Wells' career and
receiving critical acclaim as being among the best albums Wells ever produced
and even among the greatest blues albums ever made.

 Background

Record producer Bob Koester, the founder of Delmark Records who is credited with
discovering Wells along with producer Sam Charters, recalls that at the time he
was considering releasing an album by Wells, he was anxious about both the
audience for Wells' music and the expense of studio time and sidemen, but that
he liked the music too much to resist. Wells was given the liberty to select his
own sidemen and track list, without the usual limitation of songs two or three
minutes long, and the album that resulted became Delmark's then best-seller, a
distinction that had not been surpassed as of 2003.

Koester remembers particular complications working with Guy, who was incorrectly
believed to be legally entailed with Leonard Chess of Chess Records. Chess
approved Guy's participation on the album, but refused to allow Guy's name to be
listed in the credits until it was realized that his participation was not
contractually disallowed. Guy was, at the time of release, credited as "Friendly
Chap", a name proposed by Peter Brown, who later founded Down with the Game
Records in the UK, with the explanation that "A buddy is a friend, a guy is a
chap". For parts of the session, Guy's guitar amplifier was not working, and his
guitar was wired instead through the Leslie speaker of the studio's Hammond
organ. Koester said, "I've always been amazed at how rarely reviewers commented
on the guitar-organ tracks".

Koester also recalls that 15 minutes of "releasable music", including a duet
between Guy and Wells, was lost, with the tapes probably having been used later
to record a rehearsal.

Wells related to The Chicago Tribune in 1993 that the song from which the title
of the album was drawn almost didn't make the album. He had earlier recorded
"Hoodoo Man Blues" on a 78 years before, but when the song was presented to
radio personnel for possible rotation they had rejected it violently, throwing
it on the floor and stomping on it. Wells, too disappointed to want to try
again, credits Koester's encouragement with the song's presence on the album.

 Critical reception

The album, characterized by Little Labels—Big Sound as "blatantly non-
commercial", demonstrated to audiences that Chicago Blues could be effectively
captured on album. "[O]ne of the first to fully document the smoky ambience of a
night at a West side nightspot in the superior acoustics of a recording studio",
according to Bill Dahl of Allmusic, it popularized Wells, opening doors for him
at other, larger studios. But though it was only the first of many successful
albums for Wells, it remains among his most acclaimed. Rolling Stone, in a 1970
review of Wells' later album South Side Blues Jam, declared it "a classic, some
of the best blues Chicago has to offer". In 1998, The New York Times described
it as among the artist's best recorded works. In 2008, The Times declared it to
be Wells' "most celebrated album". In their 2005 biography of Howlin' Wolf,
James Segrest and Mark Hoffman make note that it is one of the albums usually
cited by critics as "one of the greatest blues albums ever released."

 Track listing

 Personnel
]]></wiki_text>
</entity>
<entity wiki_title="Harta,_Hungary" type="UKN" id="E0584545" name="Harta, Hungary">
<facts class="Infobox Settlement">
<fact name="subdivision_type"><link>Country</link></fact>
<fact name="subdivision_name"><link entity_id="E0557437">Hungary</link></fact>
<fact name="timezone"><link>CET</link></fact>
<fact name="utc_offset">+1</fact>
<fact name="timezone_DST"><link>CEST</link></fact>
<fact name="utc_offset_DST">+2</fact>
<fact name="official_name">Harta</fact>
<fact name="picture">Harta</fact>
<fact name="subdivision_type1"><link>County</link></fact>
<fact name="subdivision_name1">Bács-Kiskun</fact>
<fact name="area_total_km2">129.68</fact>
<fact name="population_as_of">2001</fact>
<fact name="population_total">3758</fact>
<fact name="population_density_km2">29</fact>
<fact name="postal_code_type"><link>Postal code</link></fact>
<fact name="postal_code">6326</fact>
<fact name="area_code">78</fact>
<fact name="latd">46.693</fact>
<fact name="longd">19.031</fact>
</facts>
<wiki_text><![CDATA[Harta, Hungary

Harta (Croatian: Hartava and Kartava) is a village in Bács-Kiskun county,
Hungary.

 Demography





Coordinates:
]]></wiki_text>
</entity>
<entity wiki_title="Mulberry_High_School" type="ORG" id="E0584546" name="Mulberry High School">
<facts class="Infobox high school">
<fact name="name">Mulberry High School</fact>
<fact name="motto">Where today meets tomorrow's goals</fact>
<fact name="established">1914</fact>
<fact name="type"><link>Public</link></fact>
<fact name="principal">George Hatch</fact>
<fact name="enrollment">1005</fact>
<fact name="students"><link>9th</link> through <link>12th</link> grades</fact>
<fact name="city"><link entity_id="E0581828">Mulberry</link></fact>
<fact name="state"><link entity_id="E0373950">Florida</link></fact>
<fact name="country"><link entity_id="E0679687">United States</link></fact>
<fact name="colors"><link entity_id="E0308567">Gray</link>, <link entity_id="E0007486">royal blue</link>, <link entity_id="E0583907">white</link></fact>
<fact name="mascot">Panthers</fact>
<fact name="district"><link entity_id="E0520386">Polk County</link> Public Schools</fact>
<fact name="location">One Panther Place
(Northeast Fourth Circle)
Mulberry, FL 33860</fact>
<fact name="coordinates">27°53′49″N 81°58′19″W ﻿ / ﻿ 27.89694, -81.97194 <link>Coordinates</link> : 27°53′49″N 81°58′19″W ﻿ / ﻿ 27.89694, -81.97194</fact>
<fact name="information">+1-863-701-1104</fact>
<fact name="website">schools.polk-fl.net/MHS/</fact>
</facts>
<wiki_text><![CDATA[Mulberry High School

Mulberry High School (also referred to as Mulberry Senior High School) is a
four-year public high school located in Mulberry, Florida, serving the city and
surrounding areas. Its enrollment is 1005 students.

 History

Mulberry's then-only public school began high school classes in 1907. In 1914, a
separate high school was constructed; it was a two-story brick building with six
classrooms and an auditorium, costing approximately $12,500.

In 1921, the first edition of the MHS yearbook was published, titled The
Mulberry Tree in honor of the city's famed mulberry tree.

In 1922, land was donated for the construction of a new high school, on the east
side of what is now Northeast First Avenue; construction was completed in 1924.
Also in 1924, MHS began inter-school football play.

During the Great Depression, many schools cut their terms or lost their
accreditation, and the state of Florida ran out of money, but MHS was able to
stay open thanks to taxes paid by area phosphate firms.

In 1955, the current school was constructed on 65 acres of land given by
Virginia-Carolina Chemical Corporation and International Minerals and Chemical
Corporation ; the old high school was converted to an elementary school,
Purcell.

 Notable alumni
]]></wiki_text>
</entity>
</knowledge_base>
